### **JEFFREY DILL**

#### jeffdill2@gmail.com | 864.430.1614

### **About Me**

I've spent the past 6+ years developing desktop and console applications. After attending a Ruby on Rails development weekend at the end of 2013, I began falling in love with web development. I spent the next several months familiarizing myself with Ruby on Rails as well as taking on an ASP.NET project at work with much success. At that point, I knew it was time to make a change and pursue web development full-time. In March of 2014 I was accepted into the Front End Web Engineering Academy at The Iron Yard. After 3 months of "jumping into the deep end" at The Iron Yard, I'm excited to start building phenomenal web applications full-time.

# **SKILLS**

### Web

- JavaScript
- Backbone.js
- Node.js
- Underscore.js
- Fabric.js
- Moment.js
- Gulp.js

- Grunt
- Parse
- jQuery
- Ruby on Rails
- PostgreSQL
- ASP.NET
- AJAX

- ISON
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Sass
- Bourbon
- Bootstrap
- Responsive Design

## **Desktop/Console**

.NET Framework

。 C#

Visual FoxPro

VBA

COM

SQL Server

SSRS

T-SQL

Visual Studio

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Heeter

August 2012 - April 2014

Developed the entire back-end and helped to develop the front-end for a web-to-print / print-on-demand solution. This included a JavaScript-enhanced client-facing web portal, SQL Server, C#, and an ASP.NET credit card payment website.

Was responsible for the data and source-code maintenance of a fulfillment project for a top health insurance organization - this project being the company's largest single source of revenue.

Helped to create and maintain the company website - Heeter.com - using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and DotNetNuke as the CMS.

## **Classic Graphics**

#### June 2010 - August 2012

Created a Job Order Entry system for the Variable Data division of the company, using 7,900 lines of VBA.

Helped to define, create, and implement many of the data standards and infrastructure that lead to the company becoming ISO:27001 certified in June 2012.

Wrote several applications utilizing Visual FoxPro, SQL Server, and Pervasive PSQL that were utilized by the Data Processing department to drastically decrease processing time, increase quality control, and eliminate human error.

#### SourceLink Carolina

June 2007 - June 2010

Designed, coded, debugged, documented, implemented, and maintained in-house data-centric GUI and console applications primarily geared towards direct-mail campaigns and their subsequent back-end tracking/reporting.

Worked heavily with several different linear barcodes (Code 128, POSTNET, PLANET, Intelligent Mail Barcode) and 2d barcodes (DataMatrix, PDF417, QR Code). My experience includes correct barcode creation and acceptable content to ensure data integrity, proper printing to ensure scan-ability, and extensive possibilities for usage when scanned (including writing the needed technology to make use of scanned data).

Helped to transition several million dollars worth of work from our Chicago division to our Greenville division to reduce organizational expenses and increase profitability.

# **EDUCATION**

### The Iron Yard

April 2014 - July 2014

Attended the Front End Web Engineering Academy. A few of the technologies covered include:

JavaScript

Express

Sass

Backbone.js

¡Query

Responsive DesignGit

Node.js

• HTML5

Underscore.js

CSS3

Parse

## **Greenville Technical College**

January 2010 - May 2010

Took two courses for self-study purposes:

- Visual Basic .NET
- Relational Databases

## **Clemson University**

August 2003 - May 2007

Graduated with a Bachelors degree in Sociology and Philosophy.